<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-10T19:29:16+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daren Palmer’s Blog</title><subtitle>Hi, I'm Daren Palmer and this is my blog. I write about programming and other stuff too (mostly programming).</subtitle><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Starting up with algorithms</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/10/Getting-started-with-algorithms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting up with algorithms" /><published>2020-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/10/Getting-started-with-algorithms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/10/Getting-started-with-algorithms.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-of-my-new-years-resolutions&quot;&gt;One of my new year’s resolutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I never liked math…&lt;/strong&gt; Until this year, until I got into programming seriously. Although I now enjoy math and science that doesn’t change the fact that I’m not very good at it. I’m getting better but I’m still not exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my only god: &lt;strong&gt;the internet&lt;/strong&gt; I discovered that algorithms and data structures are considered the fundamentals of computer science. That means that’s where I’m headed now ! Apparently two basic types of algorithms are searching and sorting algorithms. So here it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post-assets/binary_search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binary search&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post-assets/bubble_sort.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bubble sort&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just remembered that I also implemented the Sieve of Eratosthenes algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post-assets/primes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sieve of Eratosthenes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I checked my Sieve of Eratosthenes program for correctness I realized that I’d made a terrible mistake: &lt;strong&gt;my program ran for n times instead of square root of n times&lt;/strong&gt;. I was absolutely shook because I remember that my math teacher mentioned such a thing. I think it’s at that moment that I really regretted not listening more in math class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karan/Projects#classic-algorithms&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt; really helped me find projects to get started with algorithms. I’m not finished with the projects but I’m really eager to start using data structures. I’ll keep y’all up to date!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><summary type="html">One of my new year’s resolutions</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I know, I know…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/06/Django-seems-pretty-cool.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I know, I know…" /><published>2020-08-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/06/Django-seems-pretty-cool</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/06/Django-seems-pretty-cool.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-know-my-opinions-on-front-end-development&quot;&gt;You know my opinions on front-end development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’m not into Django to build websites. I don’t need to build any
websites at the moment (jekyll made the only website I needed ; this one
!) so why would I need to learn Django ? To see my projects in the
browser ! That’s the only reason why. I also want to make a website
where you could try all of the projects I’ve ever made. It would be
sooooo cool if I could create such a portfolio site I think it would
look really good for my college applications. BTW if you are an
admissions officer and you are reading this: 15 year old me doesn’t know
what the current Daren is worth but going to college to study comp-sci
is my dream. I want to hang out with people who share the same interests
as me and study and learn in the field that I have the most passion for.
With that being said, I enjoy arguments and debating and my political
views will not be the plainest you’ve ever seen but if you still think
that I could be a good fit for your school, let me in it’ll be my honor
to join your student body. &lt;strong&gt;This concludes my monolog for the imaginary
admissions officer who lives in my head&lt;/strong&gt;.
«««&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also concludes this blog post. As an update on my progress in that comp-sci book I was talking about in my previous posts: I haven’t had time to continue reading it because of the &lt;strong&gt;5 other fucking books that I have to read for school.&lt;/strong&gt; Up to now I’ve read &lt;em&gt;Albert Camus - L’étranger&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Albert Camus - Les justes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Benjamin Constant - Adolphe&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aimé Césaire - Discours sur le colonialisme&lt;/em&gt;. They were all really good books (especially Camus’s) but I also have to read &lt;em&gt;Margaret Atwood - The Handmaid’s tale&lt;/em&gt; which is a big book to read in 3 weeks especially when I still have 4 books to read for French left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep y’all up to date with my reading schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ps-read-albert-camus-hes-an-absolute-genius-who-100-deserved-his-nobel-prize&quot;&gt;PS: read Albert Camus, he’s an absolute genius who 100% deserved his nobel prize.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;9aa6320665b696ff414ca0ba5f41362c7696e336&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
      &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><summary type="html">You know my opinions on front-end development</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Tumultuous Travel Through Language Hell</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/30/My-tumultuous-travel-through-language-hell.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Tumultuous Travel Through Language Hell" /><published>2020-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/30/My-tumultuous-travel-through-language-hell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/30/My-tumultuous-travel-through-language-hell.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-all-started-with-an-urge-to-expand&quot;&gt;It all started with an urge to expand.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my programming journey with Python 3 in the beginning of 2019
and I absolutely love it. I love writing it, I love discovering new ways
to use it, I’m always amazed by the number of free libraries it has and
the number of free learning resources online make it deserving of its
reputation as the beginner’s language. And it’s exactly this reputation
that made me want to find my next love. This happened right at the
beginning of the Covid-19 quarantine in France and I decided to use my
time indoors to find the next step in my programming story (who am I
kidding? I would’ve spent the day inside even without the pandemic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it started… I opened codecademy and chose C++. I wanted to be a
big dick programmer and I like hardware so I chose C++. I enjoyed the
tutorial, finished it in a week (I wasn’t entirely dedicated to it, my
friends were harassing me to facetime with them). As anyone who just
finished the beginner tutorial of a language I set off to find a project
that was beginner friendly. All the suggestions that I found were
sooooooooo dull! A bunch of bank account management programs, accounting
programs, library management programs. I understand that these type of
projects are good to learn about custom objects and database management
but damn are they boring. Nevertheless, I wrote an absolutely crappy
library management program. I sucked ass, was super boring to code, it
wasn’t even usable and as I finished the project I thought to myself
“Wow I could’ve done that in 1/4 of the time in Python and the result
would’ve been absolutely the same. Hell ! I wanted to learn C++ to get
my hands dirty and I just couldn’t see how C++ would do that for me. So
I moved onto JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript was a fun one. The course was longer than C++ but I enjoyed
it a lot more. It was the first time I heard about asynchronous
programming and I thought it was a really interesting concept and got me
interested in backend but I didn’t have the skills to pay the bills yet
so I started with front-end and created a little calculator that is
available on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ColleSerre&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; but please don’t
go look at it because it’s absolutely the worst ; right after I got it
working I sweared that I’d make it look prettier but I remembered that I
really hate front-end coding (can’t really call it programming ; you’ll
get used to me despising HTML and CSS). I did try ReactJS after
JavaScript to start learning the MERN stack I really like JavaScript but
I really hate front-end and can’t handle the environment (I’m very bad
at managing Windows which is why I run Linux, specifically pop-Os, on my
laptop and Windows 10 on my desktop which I find crucial for gaming). I
can still code in JavaScript but my good friend Adrien Dumont is way
better than me (he’s more talented in web-development than me in every
single way and is probably going to change the web in unfathomable ways,
for real he’s an incredible guy). He and I have a course to give at my
school next year but that’s a story for another day, or post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adrien may be a good friend, a great web-developer and a low-key genius
but he is too focused on making money and getting a job at some big tech
firm and doesn’t seem to give two shits about what’s happening under the
hood. I don’t think he has any desire to study computer science and he’s
a JavaScript aficionados. Not criticizing him but he keeps choosing the
tech/frameworks he uses because it’s popular and companies want it but
not because it’s cool tech and he enjoys using it which I think is sad.
We’re 16 years old and we still have a few years till we go off to
college to code nothing but C so let’s enjoy the plethora of
interesting, fun and obscure frameworks the world has to offer !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then followed a C tutorial (in another attempt to get my hands dirty)
but I really didn’t enjoy the programming experience. After that, I read
&lt;em&gt;L’étranger&lt;/em&gt; by Albert Camus and &lt;em&gt;The Communist Manifesto&lt;/em&gt; by Karl Marx
and Friedrich Engels which made me want to make an app to read &lt;em&gt;The
Communist Manifesto&lt;/em&gt;, of course I had no idea such an app already
existed. I therefore did codecademy’s Java tutorial and began the Kotlin
tutorial but I discovered google’s Flutter framework. At last! I had
finally found my second programming love. I know, I know I’ve said
terrible things about front-end programming but this felt so much better
! The programming experience was exceptiona, the VS Code extension was
incredible, the android emulation was really handy and I’ll never forget
the thrill of flashing my first app to my phone and trying it out on my
own device. I spent about 3 weeks on the app (didn’t release it) and
experienced working with APIs for the first time yet (News API to be
precise) and put my asynchronous programming skills to good use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read my previous blogpost you’ll know that this euphoria
didn’t last very long. I enjoyed Flutter but I felt like I wasn’t really
programming and just using a complex design tool. I missed the problem
solving that came with my previous programming projects. So I
uninstalled Flutter from my computers and got obsessed by HackeRank (a
website that offers a bunch of problem solving exercises). I can’t solve
medium level problems and settle for easy but it feels like I’m really
programming and making my brain work and not just using the tools that a
team built for me without understanding the way it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so came the end of quarantine and with it came the end of my burning
question: “What language should I focus on?”. And I think I’ve finally
found an answer. You like Python? Then use Python. You’ll have to use C
in college but you’ll have classes that’ll explain the &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; way to
write C code. Developing bad habits in the most important language of
your college education seems like a bad idea…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next post will be about a book I just got called “A Programmer’s
Guide to Computer Science” by PhD William Springer. I started reading it
and I’m finding the data structures section very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><summary type="html">It all started with an urge to expand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Projects So Far</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/28/My-projects-so-far.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Projects So Far" /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/28/My-projects-so-far</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/28/My-projects-so-far.html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;up-to-now-i-have-made-a-few-projects-that-im-actually-proud-of&quot;&gt;Up to now I have made a few projects that I’m actually proud of.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you could find all of these on my
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ColleSerre&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; but it’s important for me to
reflect on all these by writing it down here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first real project was &lt;strong&gt;Scraping tool&lt;/strong&gt;. I thought (and still do)
that web-scraping was one of the coolest things you could do with
Python, which was the first language I learnt and that I consider to be
my primary language. I initially called it &lt;strong&gt;Scraping API&lt;/strong&gt; but later
realized that it wasn’t much of an API because the output was just
displayed on the CLI and not in a JSON file or any kind of reuseable
file. This is a very basic CLI project which I will maybe revive at some
point (not likely).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came Red and Gold. My biggest project yet…At first it was just
supposed to be an app to read the communist manifesto but it evolved
into a timeline, news feed and encyclopaedia of the communist movement.
It didn’t get released, I’ll maybe come around to publishing it someday
if I’m super bored but Android development and release is messy and
painful for me. It was a fun project to work on though, &lt;strong&gt;my first time
using an API&lt;/strong&gt; too. I just realised that my future self will maybe read
these lines. That’s super scary but also super cool! I’ve made the lines
above &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; so that you’ll read this part first future me. You’re
welcome! I hope you remember me and aren’t too embarrassed by 15 year
old you. If time travel exists (probably won’t and even if it does you
won’t be able to use it) give me a shout right now. At 21:17 on Tuesday
the 28th of June 2020. I’ll just wait a few minutes if anything
happens… It’s 21:17 and nothing has happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got off track. After I realised that Flutter made me dumb and that I
hated the idea of it I decided to become a big boy developer and used
HackerRank to learn about data structures, problem solving and
algorithms. It felt so much more like home! I always disliked front-end
developers. At the beginning of the year I said that I hated web
developers. That’s not true. Some web developers do some great job. It’s
not the platform that I hate, the web is amazing and I’m determined
that’s it’s the platform of the present and future, but the idea that
some people spend most of their time picking which font is the best for
their project or which color suits their landing page best makes me want
to walk into Fort Knox and pay General Mark McDonald to order his men to
fire me up with every weapon they got. &lt;strong&gt;Code should come before
esthetics.&lt;/strong&gt; I know some front-end developers will say: “but if your
tech is ugly and difficult to use no one will buy it!” to which I will
respond: “Fuck you and everyone around you. You make me want to go to my
local practitioner and ask him to prescribe me a medicinal M32 rotary
grenade launcher to cure the crippling depression you put me in. I’d
like to conclude my point on this note: &lt;strong&gt;I don’t give two shits if no
one wants to buy my tech.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not in it for the money, I’m in it for
the thrill of creating something that can change the world and make it a
better place (I know douchebag in Silicon Valley has said that but I
truly believe it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off track again. Now I enjoy coding small, fast and useful
projects in whatever language I want (usually python but I’m not married
to it like some people are). I know it’s not the best way to build an
impressive portfolio but that’s where I am now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next post will be about my trip through hell (trying to find the
perfect programming field and language). I’ve been there and I don’t
wish it to anyone, not even front-end developers from Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><summary type="html">Up to now I have made a few projects that I’m actually proud of.</summary></entry></feed>